Stephane Couvreur

Data Scientist

SUMMARY

A young team playing data scientist. I have a passion for machine learning and big data, real-time processing and distributed systems. My experience has been in computer vision for medical images, and graph analytics for anti money laundering.

EXPERIENCE

October 2018 - Present

Data Scientist Feedzai, Lisbon

• Developed machine learning models and data processing pipelines in Apache Spark and Hadoop within the Product Delivery team.

June 2017 - September 2018

Research Assistant

Great Ormond Street Hospital, London

- Embedded in a team of engineers and clinicians working on applications of data science in paediatric cardiology.
- Developed data mining and unsupervised machine learning tools in Python and R to extract useful clinical patterns in cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (CMRI).
- Accelerated medical image segmentation workflow using convolutional neural networks trained on labelled images in Tensorflow.
- Created a whole-heart computer vision workflow with an AUC of 0.752.
- The text in the entries may be of any length.
- Two successful grant applications from NVIDIA and Medtronic totalling £2500.

Projects

HACKATHONS Alibaba Cloud Tianchi, London – Jan 2018

Kaggle Days, Dubai – April 2019

Posters UCL Launch Campaign – 2016

TECHNOLOGIES

Intermediate Knowledge Matlab, C/C++, Awk, Sed,

LATEX, Git, Theano, PyTorch

Advanced Knowledge Python 3, R, Bash, PostgreSQL,

Tensorflow, Keras, Apache Spark, Hadoop △ | Estr. da Luz, 1600-160, Lisbon, Portugal

a +351 (0) 919 760 832

scouvreur.github.io
github.com/scouvreur
linkedin.com/in/stephanecouvreur

EDUCATION

2013 – 2017 Master of Engineering (1st, Hons)

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING University College London (UCL) Specialization in medical engineering and computing.

2010 – 2013 French Baccalaureate (Hons)

SCIENCES

Lycee Francois 1er Fontainebleau Specialization in mathematics, physics and chemistry (A*A*A).

AWARDS

Oct 2018 Zaickathon Brand Award

Award out of 30 teams for creating a team slide interface to Google Slides by scraping

HR data from Namely.

Sep 2017 EPSRC Summer Studentship Prize

Awarded to a summer studentship student for the best research project

from a pool of 30 candidates.

Nov 2016 Blonstein Prize

Awarded to a third year student for the best overall performance in Design.

Information

LANGUAGES English, French - fluent

Portuguese, Spanish - conversational

Memberships Data Science Portugal

References

Dr. Ganhao Data Science Lead

Feedzai, Lisbon

☑ | fjs.ganhao@gmail.com

Dr. Sauvage Project Supervisor

Great Ormond Street Hospital, London

☑ | e.sauvage@ucl.ac.uk